[Music]
he
w
[Music]
welcome hello and uh welcome everybody
to the latest episode of the askab show
I hope you're all doing very well and uh
today we're going to take questions that
you have asked in the comments so that's
what's it's going to be I'm not going to
take questions from the live chat until
the questions that have selected will
get over and before we begin let's take
a look at who all is there on the live
chat I can see Yash tiwari Chandra Shar
thi p24 Divan shuai geopolitical dub Tas
karik prna paramita Yash tiari KL aru
Basu shashwat gami nimjay Rishi LS aush
Pand himansu Raj purohit anit shti asui
Sharma Lago online Khan Rafael Ali siman
deep sing Baga Akash ba takur Pavan
Kumar sing B Mr change Vishal Kumar
Verma
sorv Ander nagri gamer Yash tiari zuban
isong sidhar sarar Rishi rajat
Duhan laki
baj Rian Vladimir Putin Akash b chasti g
Shish M luy K Gulu notan goind cookie
Senpai aush shaish sa gami way of life
by Dr aush nikil Karan nwat Akay
nikil uh Ajay Kumar akula push singla
Messi Kat Dr Jay Shankar hello Vishnu
mohanan P
Hara jalanda Reen hit Ajit s
Kabir Z jagjit Singh and so many other
people so I'm going to stop here
otherwise I'll not be able to get ahead
with the questions so thank you so much
for all being online I know it's the
tonight is the IPL final I believe right
I wonder who's playing doesn't matter I
haven't been watching the IPL so I have
no idea and thank you so much for all of
you who instead of watching the IPL are
here I appreciate
that okay let's uh let's see the
questions what questions do we have
all right um let's take
question number
one this is by kulin I am a Turk and
many of our KH or Kings before Islam
when their religion was Shamanism or
tengrism had the name isbar it is from
Sanskrit ishwara it's a very it was a
very common name among Turks we see it
all over our old inscriptions indeed
indeed isn't that interesting
many of the KH and KAG in the first
Millennium ad ad before the Turks became
islamized their names were isbar which
is from the Sanskrit isbar isn't that
interesting and let's take a look at
some evidence of that let's do a Google
search Let me put this on the screen a
Google search I'm going to search for
is okay let's let's take a
look so we are search Ing we doing a
Google search for ishar and as always
let me remind you all that Wikipedia is
not necessarily a good source of
information but let's take a look at
what Wikipedia has to say so Wikipedia
says ishara old turkic whatever this is
is a turkic name deriving from Sanskrit
ishwar and this name was carried by
different rulers in history ishak Kagan
East Guk gur Kagan 581 to 587 ad which
is the 6th Century ad isharat tulis
which is who was in the 7th Century ad
IIs ishar yagu Kagan 7th Century ad and
so on and we can take a look at some of
these individuals ish Barak
Kagan uh yeah 6th Century ad he was the
Kagan of the first tur
kaget and over here it says his name is
non- turkic obviously it's a Sanskrit
derived name so very interesting piece
of information very interesting Insight
we have been
given
by by our friend over here
kin and it is indeed correct that many
of the old KH before the islamization of
the Turks had the name isbar and who
knows what else uh what other influence
they had and let's let's understand why
there was this Sanskrit and Indian
influence when it comes to the old Turks
before islamization let's go to the
map so we're going to take a look at the
map and okay let's realign this we know
where India is and we're talking about
Central Asia northwest of India Beyond
gandhar which is Afghanistan so the St
kazakistan usbekistan turkistan Etc even
Eastern uh Ukraine Etc all of this
region is Central Asia including
kyrgistan including uh present day sang
of China and this entire region before
the Turks came into the picture this ENT
region was called skia the skians were
indo-iranian Nomads who had the this
massive uh region that they oversaw and
resided in and the skians were of well
they are classified as Iranian origin
people or Indo Iranians and their
language religion culture ethnicity was
very similar to the Indo
Iranians and we know that lots of
Indians uh Indian uh there was a lot of
Indian influence in Central Asia even
before the skians even existed there I
mean the ancestors of the skians were
were it was the result of migrations out
of India in very deep Antiquity so you
had lots of indianized Kingdoms in
present day Central Asia thousands of
years before that and when the Turks
first came into the region the origin of
the Turks was in the vicinity of present
day
Mongolia the the Huns the Shu and when
they first came into Central Asia they
would have come into contact with this
indianized people and they would have
adopted some of their customs and their
culture and that's why and that's how
this happened very interesting piece of
History not many people are aware of
this but yeah I mean I would like to
thank our friend here uh kulin for
bringing this up over here okay next
question rudrajit sarar says the Turks
permanently colonized Central Asia some
parts of the Caucasus and Anatolia but
why couldn't the Turks permanently
colonize and settle in Afghanistan
Pakistan Iran and India right it's true
the Turks
colonized Central Asia let's once again
go to the map where's the map here's the
map okay we're looking at Central
Asia so if you look at uh the Central
Asian countries today kazakistan is is
the largest one then you have usbekistan
kyrgistan Turkmenistan
aeran all of these nations all of these
presented Nations even if you look at
the Zang region of China the homeland of
the UR Etc all of these peoples are
turkic peoples that they follow the
turkic culture and they speak a tur they
speak various turkic
languages uh and ethnically they are
like 5050 you know 50% skan probably
maternally and 50% turkic that's sort of
ethnic mix they have so the Turks were
able to permanently colonize Central
Asia all of Central Asia today follows
turkey culture and speaks turkic
languages this also happened in the
Caucasus region for example aeran and
then they it went all the way into
Anatolia which is turkey present turkey
uh and Anatolia that's correct but why
but why couldn't the Turks permanently
colonized and settle in Afghanistan
Pakistan India and Iran while when it
comes to the in we're talking about
mainly the Indian subcontinent and the
western part of the Indian subcontinent
or which is Iran so the Indian
subcontinent historically was the
largest population Center in the world
and when you have such a gigantic
population a few thousand Turks coming
in is going to change nothing so the
Turks did attempt to colonize and settle
I mean they did settle in various parts
of the subcontinent they did uh first
set up the Delhi suanet then the tur
Mongol tur mugal Empire which lasted a
couple of centuries you know the orbs
and the Akbar and all that jalaludin and
zahin babers and all that so they did
that but uh they could not permanently
colonize India in the sense that they
could not change the culture of India
the way they did in Central Asia but
they could did do that in certain parts
of the subcontinent Afghanistan has been
totally changed Afghanistan is a purely
Islamic country and even the ethnic mix
in Afghanistan has changed significantly
the true native ofans are the pashun
people who are a subcontinental people
okay and the language is a
subcontinental language BTO I mean
linguists will claim that it's an
indo-iranian language or an iranic
language and all that and the afans love
that but the truth is that it's in it's
an uh it's a subcontinental language and
the pashun are a subcontinental people
but you have lots of other ethnicities
today in Afghanistan we have the turkic
peoples the the not the tajiks tajiks
are an iranic people but we have usbek
we have turkman we have the kirgis we
have even kazaks Etc so a significant in
in the hazaras obviously the hazaras
came in through a different route
through the Mongols not through the
Turks but uh same difference let's say
so the majority population of
Afghanistan even today is pashun but
there's a significant nonnative
population that can today be considered
native because they've been around for
the past 1,000 years roughly so those
are the tur and there's a lot of
intermingling between the Turks the
turkic peoples and the pashun and you
can see that in the appearances of some
of these peoples so they could actually
the Turks actually permanently change
the demographics the religion the
culture of Afghanistan and of course
Pakistan is a consequence of the turkic
occupation of India So currently
Pakistan the temporary artificial Nation
follows a non- subcontinental culture
and religion and even the language the U
language U is a conr language that is
based on
Sanskrit grammar and vocabulary but it
has a lot of vocabulary from the other
languages like the turkic languages uh
uh Arabian as well as Persian Persian I
don't mind too much because it's a
sister language when it comes to India
but uh Arabic is definitely a nons
subcontinental language and tur the
turkic languages also are non-s
subcontinental languages so they could
permanently I mean as as of now I mean
uh when it comes to the culture and
demography of Pakistan the religious
demographics it's almost like a
permanent change and Afghanistan
definitely a permanent change what about
Iran well the Arabs did the first damage
to Iran by destroying Zoroastrianism and
well completely changing the religious
demographics of Iran in just a few
decades and then the Turks did occupy
Iran okay when this fellow nadara came
and sacked Delhi and did a lot of damage
in India Indians think of him as an
Iranian Emperor but it was he was a
turkic Emperor who ruled over the
Persians
so there were turky empires in Iran as
well Iran was colonized by the Turks and
the Turks did a lot of demographic
changes demographic re-engineering in
Iran they brought in lots of peoples
lots of immigrants from the Caucasus
region who settled in Persia they
brought in a lot of aarani people in
Persia in Iran I mean lots of important
people in Persia are of aarani and
various other ethnic Origins so today if
you look at Persia only about 50% of the
people of Persia are of Persian
ethnicity only roughly 50% the rest are
either turkic or or Arabic or
aarani or pashun or Balo or whatever so
that's what happened so a significant uh
demographic reengineering of Iran was
done by the Turks if you look at the
Persian people today Iranian people lots
of them look almost you know European in
appearance the true
Persians uh the the real original persan
appearance was light brown skin dark
hair and dark eyes that's what that's
the original appearance of the Persian
people but today you have people who
look absolutely European and those are
the people who have been brought in from
the Caucasus region aeran Etc and that's
a significant percentage of the
population of Iran today so the Turks
were able to do do this to change the
demographics of Iran and Afghanistan and
Pakistan and to a very small extent
India but India is so large uh
civilization or sub Continental sized
nation that it's almost impossible to
make any significant changes lasting
changes eventually everything will get
absorbed into the mother nation
yeah okay user case whatever says what's
your opinion uh on the death of Iran's
president Mr RI look I've spoken about
this before I'll touch on this briefly
uh from whatever information that we
whatever information we have it looks
like it was an accident okay helicopters
rotorcraft are inherently un stable more
unstable than fixed Wing aircraft let me
show you a tweet of mine from some a few
years
ago where is it here we
are come on okay let's put this tweet on
the screen so this is a tweet uh This
original tweet that I've quoted here is
from October 12 2019 I don't remember
what in what context I wrote this I
tweeted this I said avoid helicopters
whenever possible they're not as
reliable as fixed Wing aircraft and then
I tweeted quoted that and said sad but
true one day after the death of that
basketball player what's his name Le not
LeBron uh what whatever that guy's name
was I forget the name I'm sure some
people in the comments will be able to
help me out with that so I tweeted that
sad but
true uh kby Bryant I think the name yeah
in in 2020 and this happens over and
over again we had the the unfortunate
demise of General bin Singh rawat then
we had a helicopter crash in Taiwan
which killed their uh Army Chief of
Staff or whatever the rank was and now
we have the death of Mr RI the thing is
helicopters are in rotorcraft are
inherently more unstable than fixed Wing
aircraft especially when you have a
rotorcraft a helicopter that is old it's
ancient that is not under this license
agreement or whatever maintenance thing
and it doesn't have GPS it doesn't have
the latest technology well it's
dangerous especially when you're flying
in flying half blind in the fog in the
clouds with h Hills not far away from
you dangerous dangerous dangerous so
from whatever information we have at our
disposal it looks like it was an
accident but let the government of Iran
do their own investigation and come up
with their findings from where I am from
whatever information I have it looks
like it was an
accident Rishi says after the death of
Ibrahim RI what's the future of the
chabahar port project the rupi real
trade India Iran and India Iran
relations in general I don't think the
death of President RI will change much
when it comes to the India Iran
relationship the India Iran relationship
is reasonably strong I mean it could
have been better was it not for the
meddling of the United States Iran is a
nation that's rich in oil and gas
petroleum and natural gas and it makes a
tremendous amount of sense I mean look
at the map of course we have to go to
the map right so where is map let us
find map
so we have map here as you can see
Persia Iran is our neighboring country
Pakistan is is a temporary aberation on
the map so you go go west from the sea
of sashtra and you enter the go through
the state of hormos and you are in in
the Persian Gulf right next to India and
this is a region that's rich in oil and
gas and India is a giant country with a
huge appetite and huge demand for for
oil and gas because we are a growing
economy and to grow an economy you need
fuel and that fuel U is typically oil
and gas it makes so much sense for India
to Source its gas and petroleum
requirements from right next door from
Iran but the Americans have been
meddling in this matter and they have
essentially arm Twisted India into not
doing this and you may say that oh we we
we are too weak I mean we should not
have given into their their threats and
all I mean are you kidding
me we are living in the real world here
right when the biggest thug in town says
that do what I say or else you're going
to do what what he says the biggest thug
in town the biggest Gunda in town that's
the US so uh despite that we we have
recently CH signed the chabahar port
project the chabahar port is over here
it's a 10-year deal which will most
likely be extended depending on how it
goes and it's going to reconnect India
with with Central Asia as you can see
India is a nearly landlocked Nation
apart from the C access that we have
gigantic C access Pakistan has locked
off has cut off our access to Central
Asia our thousands of year old historic
access to Central Asia and the Chinese
occupied Tibet essentially ensure that
we don't have any access to Eurasia as
well otherwise we could have gone
straight to Russia through the Central
Asian regions and we could have gone all
the way to Europe you know had trade
routes with Europe through over land but
all of that's been cut off so uh the
chabahar port deal will enable India to
regain some access to Central Asia also
reconnect with Afghanistan bypassing
Pakistan and that's great for Iran as
well it's great for the north south
International north south transport
Corridor which benefits Russia which
benefits Iran which benefits lots of
Central Asian and Caucasus region
Nations there is the rup real trade
which is beneficial for both Nations and
all so I think uh the death of President
RI will not make any difference when it
comes to these matters to the broader
India Iran relationship because we have
to understand first of all that the
president of Iran is not a very powerful
person the true power in Iran doesn't
lie with the
president okay it lies with the supreme
leader the supreme leader Is Not Elected
all right so understand how things work
the president is just well it's okay
it's it's just somebody who goes and
deals with the rest of the world but the
true leadership in Iran Is Not Elected
all right it's it's a permanent
leadership for now
now okay bemal says a sir a Persian
cousin here hello Persian cousin good to
hear from a Persian cousin the question
is will Iran get strong and developed
after our current government which is
going to fall soon will with help of
India obviously a strong bat on our
border is going to help us economically
well I'm not sure about when or if the
current government of persa will fall
clearly it is well known that there is a
lot of discontent within Persia with the
Islamic government in Iran it is no
secret that lots of Persians uh do not
see Islam as their their true religion
and culture Persia was forcibly
islamized by the Arabs we know that it's
it's very well known if you if you read
sh the the Shaham of
fosi you can you can see what in what
way he describes the Arabs and what they
did to Iran the Arabs were not popular
and whatever was done to Iran even few
centuries after the the fact it was
still deeply unpopular it is deeply
unpopular today also among certain
sections of Iranian Society so whether
the government Falls or not it's
I would rather not comment on that if
the people of Persia if the people of
Iran have do not like this government
well then they can take whatever action
is needed that's I would say from my
perspective an internal matter of Persia
but uh I would very much like to see
Persia Thrive and prosper for sure right
now I mean the F past few decades past
several decades many decades Persia has
been crippled its economy has been
crippled by the tremendous uh heavy
tremendously heavy sanctions that have
been imposed by the United States it's
caused a lot of suffering lot of death
and disease and whatnot the economy has
been crippled and yeah so Persia has
been treated in a in a way that's
similar to the way the Americans have
treated Cuba so uh yeah it's it's sad to
see this and I hope I I would very much
like to see Persia prosper and thrive in
the future and obviously in the future
there's going to be a common border
again between barhat and Persia the
temporary aberration will soon disappear
of the map I can assure you of that and
yeah then the region will be way more
peaceful no more terrorist regime over
here so the three nations three
neighboring Nations India Afghanistan
and Iran will be able to breathe a sigh
of relief when this threat disappears uh
no I have no ill will towards the people
of Pakistan they they are our own people
no doubt about that at least from the
the ethnic the perspective from the
ancestry perspective of course they many
of them would like to see India wiped
off the map but unfortunately it's going
to be the other way around
so in the future I would like to see lot
more cooperation between India and and
Persia bhat and Persia and I would very
much like to see Persia the people of
Persia Thrive and the nation of Persia
Prosper very much
so okay third Stone oblitum says we
haani people were also zor Austrian
until 3:30 ad Haan is of is Armenia by
the way okay high high is the Armenian
ethnicity so hayan had suddenly a stupid
King trat who converted to Christianity
and ordered all hayani people all
Armenians to convert to Christianity but
50 50% of us said no way and escaped
Haan and went to Yash Yash and Isfahan
in Persia I wonder if we are mixed in
there in India with the community un un
fortunately my family family converted
to Christianity and I was born a
Christian but at 15 I rejected it now I
don't know what I am okay okay let's
let's once again go back to the map to
uh to get the correct context of what
we're discussing so when it comes to uh
Armenia it's actually a nation that's
reasonably far away from India so you
know where India is you go westwards
there is a temporary Nation then we have
gandar we have Persia and then we have
Iraq Syria then you have Armenia so
Armenia is here in the cauas region
South Caucasus region and it's currently
under attack from all sides from Turkey
as well as aeran now arenia used to be
much larger in the past Armenia is a
very small today's Armenia is a very
small remnant of the earth while Kingdom
of Armenia which was much greater and
much larger the whole of Anatolia had
lots of Armenian origin people and like
uh our friend over here says that uh in
in the third or fourth Century fourth
Century ad there was this king called
trdat who ordered all Armenians to
convert to Christianity and lots of
Armenians did not like this so many of
them escaped some of them went to
Isfahan which is over here and then some
of them went to yasd in Iran where is
Yas can we locate yasd okay not shiras
we want to see where is
Yas okay okay okay I'm going to have to
I'm going to spend some time locating it
is it let's just take the shortcut and
say
yes okay here we have it Yas and there
are lots of Indians who zor asrian whose
name is
yasi and those are the ones who escaped
from yasda after the after the Arabic uh
Invasion and occupation of Persia y so
apparently lots of Armenians also
escaped to places like Isfahan and YZ
and and settled down there and uh it is
known I mean we know for a fact that
lots of Armenians had a presence in
India over the centuries I mean if you
go to places like Surat for example
there is an Armenian Cemetery there that
dates back at least about I don't know
four 500 years and Armenians used to
trade with trade in India and India
Indians also had a presence in the
Caucasus region in Armenia Etc you go
back 2,000 years there were Hindu
temples in Armenia that were then
destroyed and and temp and and churches
were built on top of these temples
probably by Kings such as this trat
who's being referred to
here so uh there is a significant
despite the geographical distance there
is a significant connection between
India and Armenia and yeah so Armenia is
probably one of the oldest if not the
oldest Christian Nation at some point in
time there would have been Hinduism and
some some point in time we know for a
fact that there was almost everyone was
Zoro Austrian as well and Indians were
Traders and they used to travel and they
used to go to all parts of the world so
you would have had a Hindu and Indian
presence there as well and we know that
there was an ninian presence in India as
well so yeah that is in very brief the
the history and the connection between
India Persia and Armenia Armenia has had
tragic history of late it's been even
more tragic and uh yeah there is this uh
cognitive dissonance and and disconnect
that people have between the cultures
that have been imposed upon them lots of
Ians are trying to revert back to
Zoroastrianism their ancestral uh
culture and faith and looks like there
is the similar sentiment in U Armenia as
well so yeah I I would say that I wish
everybody the best and they have to find
their own way forward in
this rodrit sarar says why does nobody
care about Armenia the first Christian
country in the world which is slowly
being devoured by aeran and turkey on
the other hand it seems like half of the
world is trying for Gaza what's the
reason behind this the reason behind
this is that everybody has an agenda
there's an agenda and the when it comes
to the Gaza thing there is a there is a
significant Lobby in the US that is pro
Palestine pro pro what shall we say Pro
Arab or Pro whatever Pro Middle
East right there's a significant Lobby
in there the Rashid lies and thehan Omar
and all the all these people and there's
a significant similar Lobby in various
uh other Anglo phone Nations the five
eyes Nations and you you know what kind
of migration has been happening
happening on an industrial scale in the
US in the UK in Europe Etc so it's it's
no uh it's no surprise therefore there
is a very strong Lobby which has an
agenda that is very Pro Gaza and that
same Lobby has a very big issue with
India as well and it brings in the
Kashmir issue whenever they feel like on
demand so there is
that and then there is the case of of
Armenia which is a helpless small
country that uh is being yeah like you
say devoured by by aeran and aeran let's
understand is a proxy of turkey it's
also a country that is supported by
Israel and the United States and Turkey
would like to wipe Armenia off the map
and create a corridor of the tur Nations
so turkey will connect with azaran which
will connect with Turkmenistan and the
other Stans and it creates a pan Turan
pan turkey Corridor at the expense of
this very ancient culture and Nation
called Armenia and that's what they
would like to do and I can assure you
that Russia would not like to see this
happen despite whatever relationship
exists between Russia and Armenia at
present Russia would not like to see
turkey make inroads in this region which
has traditionally been Russia sphere
within Russia's sphere of
influence so yeah so the world doesn't
care so look people people like to
Virtue signal that we believe in We
Believe In Justice we believe in Freedom
we believe in helping the oppressed and
all that that only works when it serves
their agenda when it comes to a nation
like Armenia which doesn't which is of
no interest or or utility to them and
they will just keep quiet about that
what about what about Tibet Tibet has
been brutalized and destroyed by China
and nobody says a word about Tibet but
Gaza Gaza Gaza yeah Hypocrites of the
first order all these
people okay user Churchill apparently
says is Ukraine is the Ukraine war going
to end soon well it's anybody's guess
when the Ukraine war will end right now
it is progressing at a very slow pace
because of the technological changes
that we have seen in Warfare
so if you look look at the lines on the
map on a week to we basis they are
changing very very slowly recently there
have been Russian Russian offensives
let's go to the map once
again so we're going to go to the map
and we're going to look at
Ukraine so uh recently there's been a
Russian offensive in the KV KV region KV
is this city over here uh which is not
very far from belgorod in Russia very
close to the Russian border uh but
overall it's been very slow progress and
the reason for this slow progress is
because there are the the entire
Battlefield environment has changed so
much uh there are all these cheap
extremely uh inexpensive drones that can
take out tanks and then people I mean
Nations like Russia Etc have been forced
to very rapidly innovate and put all
kinds of Contraptions on top of their
tanks but the the the effect of all of
these changes of these tremendous Mine
Fields of these uh loitering Munitions
of the these anti-personal drones of
these anti- tank drones and whatever
else the effect the cumulative effect of
all of this has been such has been that
on a good day you will advance 10
kilometers in your offensive on a good
day 10 kilometers is a great day
actually typically it's a kilometer or
two so everything is proceeding at a
very slow pace because of the extreme
lethality of the battlefield environment
it's almost like you've gone back to the
first world war you remember this I mean
sure you most most of you don't know but
this first world war was this protracted
long slow War kind of thing with trench
warfare and you seeing similar things
today in Ukraine so because of the
technological innovations that have come
in and which are now becoming part of
21st century Warfare we are seeing very
slow movements on the battlefronts and
based on that it looks like this could
be a war that could go on drag on for a
long period of time or Russia could end
it next week if they just choose to use
their air power because they haven't
used their air power they can flatten
Ukraine tomorrow if they wish they have
that much air power and missile power
but they don't want to do
that but uh so it depends to be it it uh
remains to be seen what course of action
Mr Putin takes but I can assure you of
one thing I mean for the past 2 three
years there have been this constant
propaganda which Indians and others have
bought into that Russia is losing that
Baku was a disaster for Russia Baku had
no strategic relevance Russia has lost
300,000 Personnel the ukrainians are
winning one Ukrainian fighter pilot to
took out 78 Russian Russian suco all
this nonsense has been has been
constantly spewed out Putin is dying
Putin has cancer Putin has some other
disease it's just a matter of months now
they have been saying this for years
since 2022 February I assure you this
war whenever it ends is going to end on
Russia's terms Russia is going to win
this war so that's what's going to
happen when it happens when it's going
to happen I cannot really tell you I am
not in the business of making
predictions I analyze probabilities I
use a quantum mechanical approach a
probabilistic
approach not a deterministic
approach okay geopolitical dub says does
Russia want Prime Minister Modi to
remain in power I think the uh the right
question the right way to frame this
question is how beneficial is it for
Russia if if Mr Modi remains in power
and how beneficial is it for Russia if
Mr Modi
doesn't remain in power and and some
coalition government comes to power in
India what are the pros and cons and
let's also throw China into the
mix so look um Mr Putin and Mr Modi get
along very well they understand each
other very well they they are both very
practical and pragmatic leaders they
both prioritize their own National
interest that and that's the best
approach when it comes to international
relations I will prioritize my national
interest you prioritize your National
interest now let's talk I'm going to
talk from a selfish perspective you talk
from a selfish perspective from your
side from my side I'll do it from from
my side and let's see if there is any we
are able to discover any convergence of
interests and if there is a convergence
of interests we're going to work
together in in those matters that is the
best way to do geopolitics in
international relations it is respectful
towards each other and it is mutually
beneficial and that's what both Mr Modi
and Putin Mr Putin do right and
obviously when it comes to India and
Russia we have almost no bone of
contention anywhere we have no disputes
anywhere we have no such problems
anywhere and we almost have strategic
alignment on almost
everything if even when it comes to
China the Russians are no friends of
China China is a problem for Russia
gigantic problem for Russia in the long
run and Russia would very much like
India to emerge as a a major power so
that it offsets
China and and will a weak miserable
coalition government in 2024 in India if
it if it happens will that be beneficial
for Russia it obviously won't be
beneficial for Russia so Russia from
this from the if you look at the logic
of pure
strategy it makes sense for Russia to
want Mr Modi to return to power to
remain in power right so yeah Russia
would very much want Mr Modi to remain
in power now what about
China what about China would China like
Mr Modi to lose the election and and
would China like want to see a weak
coalition government come to power in
India how what about
that let's look at it right rally and
logically China understands Mr Modi they
have been dealing with Mr Modi for the
past 10 years and obviously Mr Modi and
the new the this current Indian
government is a problem for China
because in the past 10 years India has
risen so much grown so
much economically and India
Haso adopt adopted a very strong
uncompromising and Hardline approach
when it comes to Chinese aggression on
the border India has given back as good
as as it gets and that's what caused the
Galvan Clash which was the which was a
symptom of China's nervousness and all
the other clashes on the border but
India has put its money where its mouth
is and it's been building infrastructure
and all that so it's a huge problem for
China when you had a soft and weak and
useless government in India it was great
for China and now you have this
government of Mr Modi so obviously it's
a huge problem for China so does China
want Mr mod to lose the election well I
would say no despite this I think Mr
xijinping would prefer Mr Modi to stay
in power why is that here's why imagine
a ridiculously stupid and hypothetical
scenario in which a weak coalition
government of 78 party 78 party
Coalition comes to power in
24 okay imagine that impossible
scenario now if you know what political
parties these are and what their leaders
are like you will see that there is a
very strong external influence in there
external as an external to India and
it's not a Chinese
influence it's a Western influence so if
such a government comes to power in
India it's going to be very strongly Pro
West now does China want a very strongly
Pro West government to appear in India
no no no at least Mr Modi has a very
strongly independent foreign policy he
is not influenced by the West
right so that is actually beneficial for
China but a a weak a government which
may be weak but which is very strongly
Pro West is a danger for China it's
going to be alarm bells for China if
that happens so
despite their issues with Mr Modi I
think Mr xijinping and the Chinese would
actually like Mr Modi to come back to
Power in 2024 and that's obviously one
hopes one hopes what's going to happen
okay Anand V 1622 says what will happen
if China attacks Taiwan there's news
coming out that the CH the Chinese naval
ships are surrounding Taiwan they're
they're doing Naval drills and exercises
in the South China Sea if they attack
Taiwan they will get they will be
sanctioned by the United States and
other countries that that are the
minions and vasal of the US and the
Chinese economy will might very well get
hit they're not like Russia Russia has
everything Russia has Anarchy but China
also has Iran they have important they
import oil and gas from Iran so what's
going to be the situation like so the
first question is will China attack
Taiwan uh once again we go back to our
best tool which is Z map so we have
China and we have the Champa sea which
is alleged which is erroneously called
the South China Sea and we have the
island of Taiwan over here and then we
have various Japanese islands near
Taiwan the closest one is yonaguni
and right now the situation is such that
the Chinese Navy the people's
enslavement Navy people's sorry
Liberation Navy has encircled thawan and
they are conducting various military
drills and exercises in conjunction with
the people's enslavement Air Force sorry
people's Liberation Air Force the
Chinese Air Force so that's the
situation right now and some analysts
are saying they're claiming that the
date of the invasion is sometime in July
in in June or July so in a month or two
from now the ch will invade Taiwan uh
that's what some people are saying all
right so that's the current situation
Taiwan is under um under a lot of stress
because it's been current completely
encircled by the Chinese who are
conducting all these drills and Military
exercises all around Taiwan and Taiwan
is essentially it it feels like it's uh
in a state of under a state of
Siege Siege it is besieged by the
Chinese so what's going to happen will
the Chinese go ahead and in with Taiwan
uh I could be wrong here but I think it
is improbable that it will happen this
year eventually Taiwan is going to face
an existential crisis
eventually uh but will it be June July
will it be sometime this year probably
not I obviously can be wrong I could be
wrong on this in this but I think it is
too early for the CH to make such a move
I think Taiwan is a very well defended
Fortress like Island it has a occupy
strategy it will cause tremendous damage
to Chinese assets to the Chinese Navy
Air Force and to anybody who tries to
actually turn up on the beaches
amphibious Landings or whatever it's
going to cause tremendous damage to
China and even if the Chinese somehow
are able to take Taiwan they will it
will be what's called a fic Victory py r
r i fic Victory which means a hollow
Victory what they will have conquered
will be a burnt out shell of an island
every everything will be destroyed tsmc
will be destroyed everything of value
will be
destroyed so then what what will they
get a burnt out shell of an island and
at what cost so I think the Chinese are
not there yet it is believed in highly
placed circles that President Xi Jinping
has given a deadline of 2027 to his
military to his Armed Forces for being
completely prepared completely ready for
an invasion of
Taiwan uh at short notice so by 2027
they are supposed to become completely
ready and capable of doing this we're in
24 I mean in case that is true obviously
we don't have any documentary evidence
of that but it is believed in very
highly
placed places that 2027 is the deadline
so I don't think it's going to happen
now but let's see who knows if something
if somebody miscalculates and orders an
invasion all hell could break lose so in
case the Chinese uh invade in case they
invade thawan uh what's going to happen
first of all the Americans will come to
the aid of Taiwan and it's not just the
Americans will come to the aid it's
going to be well Japan will definitely
get involved Japan is a puppet of the US
it is a vasal state of the US there's
more than 120 130 military bases
American bases on Japanese soil Japan is
more of a fortress than Taiwan itself
especially when it comes to the southern
Islands Okinawa Etc which is not far
from Taiwan at all and then obviously we
we also have South Korea which is
another us Fortress so in case there's
an invasion of Taiwan you could see
activity you could see the US get
involved you could see Japan get
involved you could see South Korea get
involved if South Korea Korea gets
involved then North Korea will get
activated and this could very
rapidly very
rapidly uh run out of control
so that's what could get what could
happen the Americans will also impose
sanctions on tha on China which will
also hurt the US economically economy
very badly because the US and Chinese
economies are joined at the hip you
cannot damage one without damaging the
other the US gets almost everything from
China you know cheap manufacturing and
all not so cheap anymore but yeah and
yeah I know that China has Iran from
which it gets important oil and gas
supplies but have you considered where
that those supplies come from so when it
comes to China it gets a lot of supplies
from the poran Gulf from Iran also from
from Saudi Arabia etc etc etc all of
that comes through the sea route and
where does all that come from from this
straight the straight of malaka this
tremendously narrow straight and if you
want to go through the straight of
malaka where do you have to pass through
you have to pass through the Andaman in
nicobar island
chain right so
that will be a problem for China India
holds the key to Chinese good behavior
actually when it comes to the Andaman
and nikobar Islands because of India's
capability very good very strong
capability of being able to blockate the
malaka strait India can choke off that
straight interdict all traffic at
will and not just through visible means
but invisible
means all right so let me not elaborate
so yeah I don't think China is in a
position to do any of this right now but
who
knows happy faces 228 says in CBS class
12th n CER English book there's a
chapter called The Tiger King he was an
Indian king in this chapter the author
has said that the Tiger King Grew From
an English Nanny watched nothing but
English movies and drink and drank the
milk of only English cows like all the
other kings of the time
I don't understand why were the Kings
mentally
colonized it's understandable for normal
people didn't they have any self-respect
okay it's a good question by the way
okay we have to understand what happened
what changed in 1857 1857 was the Great
War of Independence that almost all of
India participated in and because of
various reasons we ended up losing the
war of independence and the British able
to uh defeat the various Indian Kings
and kingdoms that had risen up against
them and then that was the end of the
rule of the East India Company and it
then the British crown took over ruling
India from that time and there were
tremendous
repres you know repres against IND
Indians at least 10 million Indians were
killed in the decade after 1857 in Acts
of
Revenge okay that's what the British did
in India now that's not all that
happened in 1857 the British were able
to somehow win the war in 1857 and then
what happens what happened after the
British won the war they killed off
every single Royal lineage that had
fought against
them wiped them off killed them
off killed the Kings killed the Queens
killed the children killed any relative
who had a pretense to the throne and
then what they would do is they would
take some distant far-off relation of
that king or queen and install that
individual as a puppet on the crown and
these were the princely
states that we know
of so every single king or queen in a
princely state in India who was still
nominally in power after 1857 was a
puppet of the British
now it doesn't mean they were all
traitors some of them understood that
the only way to serve their people to
serve their subjects was to
compromise and accept the suty of the
British so they had to accept a uh
British political agent in their Court
which meant that there were no longer
independent or Sovereign kingdoms they
could not really maintain any armed
forces they would have collectors on on
their territory even today we have
collectors District collectors what do
they collect what do today's District
collectors collect in the old days in in
the 19th century 20th century during the
British occupation they collected Indian
wealth obviously it was extortion it was
the drainage of India's wealth out and
resources out of India that's what
collectors were for so these princely
states they they would have collectors
who would give money straight to the
British
Treasury and they would have political
agents who would monitor all of their
moves and ensure that everything went as
per British instructions so all of these
kings queens princely States kingdoms
whatever first class second class third
class whatever they all were British
puppets some of them were not
collaborators if you look at
the what's the temple Shri anant padavan
anant padmanaba Swami Temple the one
where you have trillions of dollars
worth of gold and jewelry I mean that
King that princely state whoever was
running that they did not allow the
British to know what was in the temp in
the temple otherwise it would all have
been taken away so many temples were
were drained of their wealth in this
matter trillions of dollars worth of
treasure in today's money from each
Temple so the Shri anant padmanaba Swami
Temple today
has an incredible amounts of wealth in
just one Temple more than the GDP of
most Nations okay and it is thanks to
the to the to the rulers of that
princely state that the British did not
get wind of this so some of them were
actually good people but most of them
were simply collaborators or puppets
installed by the British people who did
not have any actual claim or legitimacy
to the throne there are many examples I
will not name these examples because
it's going to offend and upset a lot of
people lots of feelings will get hurt if
I name
them okay but you can do your own
research you can do your own due
diligence
so all of these people eventually became
anglicized they had to send their
children to study in the UK they had to
have English nannies and everything
English and if you look at their
descendants today they are all more
British than the
British so overall slowly they became
mentally colonized and they lost all
dignity and all self-respect most of
them not all of them most of them if not
many of
them okay um and yes that is
what happened and if you look at the way
the British destroyed the lineage of of
various Kings for example how the the
manner in which they destroyed the
lineage of Maharaja Ranjit Singh then
you will understand how what happened in
those days so yeah so it's it's no
surprise that these Indian Kings many of
them were more English than the English
themselves rodit sarar says the era of
the Cold War there was a significant
rise of Arab nationalism nationalism in
the Arabic countries then why didn't the
formation of a United Arab country take
place even
though a significant portion of people
backed the idea was it because of
internal friction or foreign
intervention is good question once again
excellent question okay let's go back to
the map to to to put everything into
context so we're talking about the
Arabic region the larger Arabian region
beyond the Arabian Peninsula so we have
Saudi Arabia today we have the various
Arabic Nations Yemen Oman UAE Iraq well
okay let's call Iraq Arabic Jordan Syria
Israel and
Egypt these are the Nations that we are
talking about so in the 1950s Etc 50s
60s you had very strong leaders in the
region uh at various points in time I'm
not saying they were all contemporary
contemporaries of each other but you had
leaders at various points in time like
Nasser in Egypt you had Saddam Hussein
Alti in Iraq you you had somebody like
muamar Al Gaddafi in Libya which is
another Arabic nation that we are
talking about it's today it's an Arabic
Nation more or less uh and so on so you
had these leaders who were strong men
who were very big nationalists many of
them were all three of these guys that
are mentioned were secularist leaders
they understood the dangers of
radicalism and all that and uh they ran
their countries in a remarkably secular
Manner and there was this this sense of
nationalism pan Arabic nationalism among
the peoples of this region but the
problem is that this region was under
the very strong influence of the two
superpowers
okay in in in in a variety of ways the
two superpowers which is the US and the
USSR we're talking about the 1950s 1960s
and and so on so there was a cold the
Cold War was going on and there was
great power competition super power
competition in this region for for
influence and control and various Arab
nations were under the influence of one
of one or the other of these two
superpowers so there is that so that is
one factor that prevented the um
formation of a long-lasting United Arab
country then you had kingdoms like Saudi
Arabia and kingdoms like
Jordan which which did not want a United
Arabic nation and they were deeply
distrustful mistrustful of people like
Nasser and Saddam Hussein Etc whom they
they saw as socialists and uh who they
saw as threats to their own uh survival
and legitimacy of Their Kingdoms there
was that and then there was the uh
inequality economic inequality between
the Nations like the Arabic Nations like
for example Saudi Arabia was extremely
rich in oil Iraq was extremely rich in
oil but some of the other countries like
like Libya for example like Egypt uh
Syria for example were not that rich in
oil so if you have a United um Nation
then why would you give away your wealth
to those who well in your eyes don't
deserve it there was that so there were
multiple reasons for this this and
obviously there was a shortlived
experiment of the United Arab Republic I
think it was from 58 to 61 or something
like that you can look up the dates I
don't remember dates I don't memorize
dates some somewhere around 1958 and
1961 I think if I'm not mistaken so
there was a shortlived experiment of a
United Arab Republic which was uh which
comprised Egypt and Syria and obviously
it did not last long so yeah because of
these factors because of all these
reasons great power politics super super
superp power competition uh mistrust
from Saudi Arabia and Jordan and all
these factors that this could not really
happen uh yeah that's the
answer okay R sarar has asked a lot of
good questions I've been able to take
only a few of those but I I like the
questions keep asking so the question is
how did the Champa Kingdom of Vietnam
fall all right it is a kingdom that war
that existed in present day Vietnam the
present day Vietnam region but it was
not a Vietnamese Kingdom all right
firstly there's that now secondly where
was it located we have to orient
ourselves and look at the map so we know
where India is let's go eastwards
Eastward we go to Southeast Asia we go
we cross Brahma Desh which is Myanmar we
cross swabi which is Thailand and then
we come to Vietnam and Tra was located
in the southern part of Vietnam so you
have this uh as you can see on the map
you have Vietnam you have Cambodia you
have
Laos uh and you have the so-called South
China Sea which was historically the
Champa sea so the Champa kingdom was
also called
chapura it was an indianized Kingdom
located in in what is now Central
Vietnam and South
Vietnam okay that's where it was located
and it it was a very long lived Kingdom
from approximately the 2nd Century ad to
the 16th 17th almost 18th century ad
that's La that's how long this Kingdom
lasted and it was known for its very
rich culture okay very rich culture
Hindu culture to some extent there was
some some Buddhism as well so Hindu
religious influences Buddhist religious
influences later on and tremendous
achievements in Arch Ure in culture and
in Maritime trade so uh it was
established sometime in the 2 Century ad
and uh its capital was
singapur in the present day this region
Central Vietnam
Quang or somewhere around that region
okay uh that's where the the uh capital
of this kingdom was and then it it
underwent a long period of expansion and
great prosperity and its territorial
extent grew significantly and it had
multiple capitals at various points in
time and it it uh there was tremendous
cultural architectural achievements the
construction of lots of Hindu temples
you can find lots of Sanskrit
inscriptions in this region and uh you
will find shite temples you will fight
shivalingas Ganesha mortis and so much
more but eventually as with all kingdoms
there was pressure from outside from the
Viet the D Viet Kingdom the Vietnamese
Kingdom and the Champa Kingdom began to
fragment into smaller principalities
then in the in the 13th 14th century the
the great three Kubla Khan invaded this
region the grandson of the Conqueror
chingis Khan and the invasion was not
successful the Mongol invasion of CH of
of Kubla Khan was not successful but the
conflict it drained the resources of the
Champa Kingdom and further weakened the
Kingdom so this was in the 13th or 14th
century the Mongol invasion and then
because of the pressure coming from the
uh expanding dth Kingdom Etc uh the
Champa Kingdom kept on losing territory
and by the late 15th century early 16th
century Champa was a significantly
smaller Kingdom and then you had an
invasion by the diet and they captured
the capital which was via and destroyed
much of the infrastructure of Champa and
whatever was left of Champa persisted
till the 17th or 18th century and
eventually it was fully absorbed into
the Vietnamese uh Kingdom okay so so
that's essentially what happened so that
is how the Champa Kingdom of Vietnam
fell but it was a tremendously Rich
culturally Kingdom it is renowned for
its Hindu Kingdom Hindu temples temples
at at Mison it's a temple complex and
there are other ones as well it is Po
nagar and so on beautiful architecture
beautiful designs of these temples
influenced by Indian style Indian
architectural style architectural Styles
and Indigenous Styles so very syncretic
beautiful culture lots of carvings
beautiful iconography
sculptures sculptures of Lord Shiva Lord
Vishnu Lord Brahma and Champa was a very
significant tra
trading Kingdom Maritime Kingdom it had
a huge navy it dominated the South China
Sea which was called the Champa SE at a
certain point in time the Champa kingdom
was a wasal of the Chola Empire as well
they had tremendous ship building
capabilities they had Advanced ship
building techniques which led to its
prowess in trade and Naval Warfare and
obviously it Champa played a crucial
role in spreading Indian culture C and
religion and art and architecture and
whatever else across southeast Asia you
find lots of Sanskrit inscriptions in
this region which tell you about uh
which give us historical and cultural
insights in into how this kingdom was
governed what the society was like and
so on so forth so today the legacy of
this kingdom is preserved in the
architectural ruins the cultural
artifacts the sculptures the uh The
Monuments and various historical records
but today the champas is called the
South China Sea and this name was given
by the idiotic westerners and they
actually did China a huge favor by doing
this well yeah there you have
it another question by rodit sarar is it
true that India culturally dominated
China for over 2,000 years without
sending a single soldier across the
border or is it that one of these those
India never invaded anybody for 2,000
years propaganda no India it's not true
that India did not invade any Kingdom or
any other country for 2,000 years India
has been just like any other Nation any
other Kingdom any other Empire culture
whatever civilization India has also
done its fair share of invading and
conquering but India did not ever invade
China so once again let's go to the map
because that is what helps us understand
so today's China is not historical China
this is the greatest extent of China
that you have ever seen what we are
seeing on the map right now see there is
something called Tibet
B which has been absorbed by China in
the 1950s and India allowed this to
happen there is something called sang
East turkistan which has never been
Chinese which is currently part of China
and then there is much more this inner
Mongolia half of Mongolia is currently
occupied by China the whole of manua is
occupied by China and so on and so forth
all right so China currently is is much
larger than what historically it was the
Great Wall of China is somewhere in the
middle of China and that was actually
the CH the extent of
China now uh India did not ever send a
soldier into China but India sent trade
Caravans to China uh trading missions to
China and these trade missions because
of the genius of our emperor keska what
keska did was that he sent lots and lots
of trade missions to China to trade with
the Chinese but with each trade Mission
he sent Scholars as well so you would
have Buddhist mon and and and Brahman
Scholars would go along with these trade
missions to China with Indian uh texts
sutras and whatnot and eventually the
Chinese started demanding started
sending ambassadors to Indian Kings
requesting and pleading with Indian
Kings to send Scholars to translate
various Sanskrit texts and sutras Etc
into the Chinese language and uh and you
had many great Scholars who became very
renowned in China One of the examples is
uh kumara Jaa I mean various Chinese
Kings fought each other they went to war
with each other so that they could have
kumarajiva in their Court that's one
example and the kumarajiva was was the
son of a of an Indian
Kashmir uh father and a princess from
the sang region from the cucha region I
believe uh he was one of the great
Scholars one of the great SCH
there were other great Scholars like
buddh badra like bodhidharma bodhidharma
is very famously the the founder of kung
fu uh he was the the chief monk in the
Shaolin Temple and he is the guy who
taught this martial art to the Chinese
which is now called Kung Fu it was an
Indian martial art so uh China has been
deeply
deeply uh influenced by Indian culture
inculturated and civilized by India uh
China even today has the lest practicing
Buddhist population in the world whether
you realize it or not and uh there's
tremendous Indian influence in China the
Chinese government today tries to
minimize the visibility of this because
it is very inconvenient isn't it this
fact that there was Zero Chinese
influence in India but there was
tremendous Indian influence in China the
question is why was there no 2,000 years
the two cultures the two civilizations
were interacting okay okay and for 2,000
years there is tremendous Indian
influence in China in so many ways it's
now become part of Chinese culture and
lifestyle okay that's how deep it is the
Indian influence in China but how come
there was no reverse influence into
India there is not an ounce of Chinese
Cultural influence in India why is that
so that tells you which was the greater
cultural power right and that's what is
an inconvenient fact that that the
Chinese don't like
anyhow yeah there you have
it balam
Putin says very recently I came across
information that opened my eyes the
average Indian subcontinental life
expectancy was around 30 years during
the British Raj same for the African
colonies that were very rich cultures at
one time surprisingly when I saw the
so-called Western Nations their average
life expectancy at that time was around
60 years then I concluded that the that
the oppressors lived a good life with
their people and the victims lost their
lives still some idiots say that the
colonial era was necessary for India it
is something that was a great Boon for
India I'm talking about the colonial Ira
correct me if I'm wrong this is a great
data point that you that you have
mentioned when the British left
India in
1947 the average life expectancy in
India was 31 years the average person
would live 31 years and then die if you
live to 41 you were very
lucky imagine the average person dies at
the age of 31 and then you have people
like you know all the great historians
and Scholars and whatnot who say that
the British rule was the best thing that
happened to India they gave us the
Indian language they gave us Railways
they gave us education because Indians
had no education of their
own they gave us the Judiciary because
Indians had no Judiciary they gave us
the rule of law because Indians were
barbarians who lived and jumped off
right the truth is that the British
occupation of India 2250 years was the
most disastrous thing that that happened
to India they completely
de-industrialized India India was the
world's first fully industrialized
civilization India had Industries in
every domain you can imagine India made
the world's largest and most powerful
ships today you won't believe it because
you haven't seen any of those ships when
Wasco the G
reached East Africa he thought he had
the most powerful and best ship in the
world and then he saw an Indian ship
which ship which was like four times the
size of a ship and that was an average
Indian
ship in East Africa Indians had a
presence in East Africa for centuries
for thousands of years India was a fully
industrialized civilization we had
Industries in every field every domain
you can imagine the British completely
de-industrialized India and destroyed
India's economy they drained everything
of value out of India the railways they
built were the infrastructure of
occupation and
extraction the Judiciary they brought in
was designed to serve them the
British the education system they
imposed on India after destroying
India's indigenous system was designed
to mentally enslave India and it has
worked
brilliantly they brought in Christian
missionaries to destroy India's culture
and that is still at work right now and
they destroyed
India's
population through hundreds of
artificially created famines and by the
time they left the average life
expectancy in India was 31 years and
these
Geniuses they say that the British rule
was the best thing that happen in India
incredible that we have such traitors
and gangadin Among Us the problem is
many of us believe this nonsense because
our teachers teach us this stuff Lord
rippen was so nice Lord William benck
was a great
reformer Lord whatever else did whatever
else the best thing that happened in
India was the reforms brought in by the
British because before the British came
in Indians were
barbarians right so that's what we are
taught and that's what most of us
believe and when one says this one gets
a lot of abuse and push back so yeah
idiots absolute idiots I mean learn how
to think critically willia
okay Vishnu says where can I read more
about this this quote the British chief
of 1921 India census said we pan hold
everyone and if we could not find a cast
for them we labeled them with hereditary
occupation we deplore the cast system
and its effect on social and economic
problems but we are largely responsible
for the system we deplore and vishno
says I can't find this quote anywhere
okay let me help you out
so let me put something on the
screen
um okay this is a research
paper it's a research paper let's remove
this and let's look here I'm going to
read this out this was
posted in a in July
204 by aay Vari from Stanford University
and Emmanuel bomb from the George
Washington University It Was Written in
2014 abstract this paper explores the
relationship between British colonial
rule and contemporary conflict in India
we argue that colonialism generated
deep-seated grievances among tribal and
low cast communities that have
ultimately resulted in armed conflict in
rural areas we identify three mechanisms
that have given rise to conflict first
the British exacerbated land inequality
in rural areas by granting land
ownership rights to zamindars and
commandeering Forest lands upon which
tribal populations rely for sustenance
second the British State refi social
inequalities in tribal and low cast
areas through their systematic
categorization and ranking of cast and
tribal communities finally the British
instituted a new bureaucratic apparatus
that cemented these social inequalities
through administrative practice thereby
fostering distrust of India's legal
system among low cast and tribal groups
the hierarchal social and exploitative
economic relationships that originated
during the British colonial period have
had long-term deleterious effects on
political stability in the countryside
and the NEX conflict and so on so forth
are a consequence of that let's take a
look at this paper and I'm going to take
some time and read through some of it
and this is very important okay so I'm
going to go down here okay it's the
paper you can check it
out
uh okay the rise of the British in India
in the 18th and 19th centuries initiated
a period of widespread peasant Revolt
throughout the country against the
British historians have noted that the
amount of peasant violence and the
British rule was considerably more
severe than that which which had
occurred under pre-colonial powers like
the Turks the muls since historians have
written extensively about how colonial
rule affected Indian peasants in adverse
ways we do not delve into this here
instead we focus on three main
mechanisms that led to the deterioration
of peasant living conditions firstly new
landh holding systems second new
discriminatory policies against tribals
and low casts by the British and they
are today worshiping the British and
third the introduction of Highly
undemocratic bureaucratic institutions
that were responsible for implementing
these discriminatory policies okay uh so
zamindars the British radically
disrupted the existing landholding
systems of India when they became the
Paramount rulers of the subcontinent
their new policies led to an increase in
the power of zamindar zamar said existed
in the pre-british period but were
intermediaries of ruler they were
Revenue agents and did not have a
proprietary right on on the land however
the British administrators drawing on
the horrific English model instituted a
new system of L tenure in which
zamindars were given private property
rights this was done with the hope of
incentivizing them to make reinvestments
in their land but in effect it led to
higher levels of land inequality and
social unrest under the new system
peasants became tenants at will and
could be displaced from the land from
for any reason consequently land be
began to concentrate in the hands of the
zamindars so that's how Indians lost
their land today nobody has land of
their own in the united provinces modern
day utar Pradesh for example 100% of the
land by Independence was owned by less
than 5% of the of the population other
such examples they are giving this
displacement led to a massive peasant
Insurrection in the 20th century mopla
rebellion was which had religious
reasons related economic forces induced
presence to substitute cash crops for
produce resulting in an increased
prevalence of famines this was done
deliberately to create these artificial
famines an estimated third of the
population of Bengal perished during the
brutal Famine of 1770 for
example and so on so forth the second
major change during the British period
was the introduction of several new
policies that discriminated against
tribals in low casts the British
instituted discrimination against
tribals and low casts it was not
inherent in Indian Society do you read
this the British instituted these
policies that discriminated against
tribals in low casts and exacerbated and
cemented social inequalities that had
been in place prior to the arrival of
the British for example the British
instituted new Criminal tribes
legislation that pertained to certain
tribes with a history of criminal
Behavior this legislation criminalized
every member of a so-called criminal
tribe including those who had never
committed a crime tribes were highly St
matized prevented from traveling freely
and often jailed for not reporting their
movements uh it was noted that it may be
said that a much larger percentage of
these tribes were led into criminality
by giving them the stigma of criminal
tribes the British also disrupted tribal
life in other more subtle ways such as
the introduction of a monetary economy
to replace a barter system and the
influx of Christian missionaries into
tribal areas the British likewise
implemented policies that re fight the
social inequalities inherent in India's
cast system though cast existed prior to
the British rule colonialism and more
specifically the desire on the part of
the colonial administrators to simplify
and systematize a complex in foreign
Society led to an emphasis on cast that
was previously unknown in India the
first census conducted in 1871 1871
attempted to place thousands of diverse
jati groups into a four tired Verna
structure artificially done by the
British promoting widespread cast and
onism especially among those designated
as so-called backward or Untouchable
casts by the British by the British by
the British read properly WC plowden
cast census Commissioner of India noted
that the British would simply designate
as
Untouchables Those whom the popular
voice designates is inferior do you
understand who designated people as
Untouchables the
British in 1901 the census began to rank
cast groups El Middleton
director of census operations for Punjab
Leed laid out the delerious effects of
these new policies cast in itself was
rigid among the higher casts but
malleable among the
lower we pijun hold Everyone by cast and
if we could not find a true cast for
them we labeled them without the with
the name of a hereditary occupation we
deplore the cast system and its effects
on social and economic problems but we
the British are largely responsible for
the system we
pretend to
deplore I'm going to stop here I've been
saying this for a long long time but
nobody bothers to do some research and
find the
truth that's why I read all this out
find this article let me put that on the
screen once again I'll put the title out
there at least you can Google the title
at least that much you can do
colonialism and armed conflict in the
Indian Countryside by aay vesi and
Emmanuel
title
bomb read it if you have any interest in
knowing what happened to your country
and to your society and how it has been
destroyed by the
foreigners next
question okay padmawati sarasvati says
you've never answered any of my
questions don't ignore it again okay
we're taking it now I want to know about
the details of how ancient India was a
democratic nation and how could have
ancient India been a democracy if a
King's son only had the right to succeed
his father
okay
was ancient India a democratic Nation
firstly the nation state system came
into existence in the 16th 17th
centuries somewhere around that time
with the Treaty of West failure and
today we have nation states but some of
these are still
monarchies so India historically was not
a nation
India historically was a civilization
India still is a civilization today
India is a civilization state but it is
forc fitted into the mold of a nation
state first that is the first point
India has always been a civilization in
various forms a single Empire a
collection of kingdoms it's a cyclical
process now when it comes to democracy
we are
taught you the lady who's asking this
question would have been taught that
democracy originated in Greece Greece is
the mother of democracy right that's
what everybody tells us that's what the
the Western historians would like us to
believe let's try and understand the
nature of Greek democracy two and a half
thousand years before today h around
that time democracy apparently emerges
in
Greece yes in those days you had city
states in Greece you had Athens you had
thieves you had Sparta and so on and so
forth city states and over there
apparently you had democracy you could
elect your officials and blah blah blah
now the question I would like to ask is
who could vote and who could stand for
election all right who was allowed to
vote and who was allowed to stand for
election first point to be noted this
Society the Greek society was a slave
owning Society a significant percentage
of the population was slaves there were
Greeks but they were slaves now if a
significant percentage of the population
even if it's let's say 3% or 5% if a
percentage of the population is slaves
and they don't have the right to vote or
stand in elections do you call that a
democracy that's Point number one
second women could not vote or stand for
election that's 50% gone H in this
democracy thirdly
peasants could not vote or stand for
election only the nobility could vote or
stand for election the nobility would
have been what 3% 5% of the population
at
most so in in this so-called democracy
only 5% at Best of the population could
either Vote or stand for
election and if you take the women out
it's just 2 and a
half% is that a democracy nobody will
raise questions about the democ
so-called democracy in Greece but then
we will ask questions about
India
H in the us. you know the US they said
the US is the oldest democracy and the
Americans claim India is the largest
democracy and us is the oldest democracy
when the United States was
formed did black people have the right
to vote or stand for election no no no
no no no no no no no no no they were
slaves did the genuine the true
indigenous natives of America the Native
Americans have the right to stand for
election or vote no no no no no read the
American Declaration of Independence it
calls them
Savages no no no they could not vote
then among the whites the occupiers and
Invaders could women vote no no no no no
women could not vote but America is
democracy
and among the white males could people
who did not own property vote no no no
no no but America is a democracy what a
godamn joke it is you know
Switzerland you have heard of
Switzerland the small little Nation
there are parts of Switzerland where
women could not vote until the 21st
century I kid you note I'm not joking
look it up you learn how to use Google
Google search in certain parts of
Switzerland until the 21st century women
did not have the right to vote but
nobody raises questions about
Switzerland now let's talk about
India we had voting in India back in the
day back in the day like like really
really long ago thousands of years ago
but we had Kings and Emperors so India
was a hybrid system a hybrid system at
the top you had hereditary kingdoms and
hereditary dynasties at the bottom at
the Grassroots level the
people in the cities towns Villages Etc
would vote to elect their own officials
who would deliver
governance and have a voice in the year
of the
king that's how it was India was always
a hybrid
system and there was another form of
democracy in in the sense that Kings had
a council of advisers who were
elected and they would advise the king
as to what to do and the King typically
had to listen to what they had to
say uh so that's the kind of system we
had in India it was a hybrid system it
was democracy at the Grassroots and
lower levels it was hereditary monarchy
either kingdoms or Empires at the top
that's the form of democracy we had show
me any democracy the world that is
perfect no you won't find it there is no
such thing as pure democracy pure
democracy is the rule of the mob you
don't want that is the US a democracy
today is the US a democracy
today we know we know that China is not
a democracy it's a single single party
State single party Nation the Chinese
Communist party is the only party that
is allowed to exist we know North Korea
is not a democracy there's only one
party and and one family that rules
is the US a democracy how many political
parties have any representation anywhere
in the nation two parties the US is a
two party
State two- party state every agenda has
to be fitted forcefully into one of the
agendas of the one of the two parties
and both the parties have the same
corrupt dealings with the oligarchs with
the military industrial complex with the
whatever else and both the parties have
the same foreign policy
okay and where's the political party for
the Hispanic people where's the
political party for the Native American
people where's the political party for
the black lgbtq people in India we have
a political party for everything we have
thousands of political parties that's
AAL democracy today so let's not
question our own history there is no
such thing is a perfect democracy India
is not a perfect democracy
today our constitution has never been
ratified by the people of India you call
this
democracy the US Constitution hasn't
hasn't been ratified by the people of
the
US When It Was Written the constitution
of the US it was put to a vote but only
white wealthy white landowning males
were allowed to vote which means that
the vast majority of the population of
the US could not vote that's not
ratification it's undemocratic so there
is no real democracy in the world
democracy is an illusion but that's my
point all right that's how it goes might
is right is the way the world actually
works you got got to be realistic and
practical and get used to The Facts of
Life next question by aam Pratap Singh
okay the Persian and Indian
civilizations have been known to have
good relations to have had good
relations with each other during the
Medieval Era I mean much before for the
Medieval Era the medieval the Medieval
era is the uh second Millennium ad which
is not good relations but yeah
historically going back the past 3,000
years before the islamization of Persia
we had excellent relations with Persia
so that's what the point is being made
here so what about the sassanian
invasion of the kushan Empire and the
aimed invasion of the Gandhara region
excellent question so I'm sure those of
you who watch uh uh who watch this show
regularly would know that I have said
this all the time that India and Persia
have always had the best of relations
until the Arabic conquest of Persia and
before the Arabic conquest of Persia
India and Persia never went to war and
Persia always expanded militarily
westwards but never eastwards towards
India then what about the sassanian
invasion of the kushan Empire which
happened in the third fourth Century ad
and what about the ained invasion of the
gandhar region around uh 4 500 BC what
about that excellent question excellent
question like it I like it very much so
let's take a look at the
map to understand U what we're talking
about so was I right was I wrong I mean
that that's a very intelligent question
to ask to it allows me to
clarify what I have been saying because
this is an important point that you're
raising so okay before I put the map on
we know the map of India and Iran no big
deal it's no big news there let me show
you something called the bhagana
inscription the bistone inscription let
us discover that and I'm going to I'm
sure I've done this at some point in
time in the past two three years but let
me do it again let me read this out for
you this is the bhagan inscription now
called the biston inscription it's
bhasan was a town in Persia it's a it's
a site of ancient monuments in including
this very famous inscription of the
persan king d d the great uh who lived
in the sixth to fifth centuries BC okay
so here's what he writes I don't know
how to read the uniform script but I'll
read the
transliteration okay he
[Music]
says nap
he says that I am d The Great
king I am the king of kings I am a
Persian king I am the king of the duus I
am the son of vaspa I the grandson of AR
Aras Aras and I am an acced King it
sounds very much like Sanskrit because
it was a descendant language of Sanskrit
now
so he's talking about his lineage my
daddy was vaspa his daddy was uh arama
Aras AR's Daddy was Arya RNA Arya rna's
Daddy was chish pish and chish pes's
father was hakam Manish the great
founder of the Empire and he goes on and
on and on about this so let's look at
the next uh part of the
inscription in which he talks about the
kingdoms that he
rules so he's talking about Aur Mazda G
gave me all these great Boons I rule
paraa uja which is ilam babush which is
Babylonia Aura which is Assyria arabaya
means the Arabic regions muda which is
Egypt uh Draya means the Nations by the
the sea sparda means lyia Yona means the
yavana Nations Greece Mada means media
Arma means
Armenia K Kuka means capadia of today's
today's Capia parava means paria zaka
Hara means chasia sarasti
region it's it's named after the sarasti
it doesn't mean the actual sarasti
region then you
have uas Mia chasia bakis is Bia which
is uh closed to Afghanistan sugua is
closed to Afghanistan and Gandara itself
and skia another places so he says that
he ruled Gandhara and this region okay
so I'll I'll leave it at that I'll not
go and read the whole thing so daros
ruled gandar Afghanistan okay and he
actually came all the way to the
river parush or something which uh one
of the rivers in the sapnu region so he
kind of had a presence in the Indus
Valley he ruled parts of the Indus
Valley D daos the first the great daos
so there is that okay daros ruled parts
of the Indus Valley and he ruled
gandhar which was historically India
Afghanistan Chandra Gupta Moria and the
Moran Empire took Gandhara back later on
and then we also have the sassanian
invasion of the kusan
Empire The kushan Empire so this is the
when the kusan empire was declining and
they no longer had great Kings the
sasanians which is another Iranian
Dynasty they went to war with the
kushans and took Paths of kusan
territories much of those territories
they took from the kushans were Central
Asia the Stans because keska had
conquered the Central Asian region from
the Aral to the Caspian SE let's put
that on the map once again map is very
important sorry not this not this I'll
put the map on the screen where is map
here
so today you don't see much of the araly
but it exists over here so that is uh
Kazakhstan and the Caspian Sea is uh is
again Kazakhstan turkistan Etc so the
Empire of keska touched the shores of
the Caspian Sea and the Aral SE and it
included parts of Tibet and much of
present day sang including the tarim
river basing region gigantic Empire
keska had conquered and when the kushan
Empire started declining sometime around
the third fourth Century ad then what
happens obviously there's going to be
pressure from the neighboring kingdoms
and the cenans took over those regions
those Central Asian regions also gandhar
I would imagine okay so when a kingdom
declines you will see this natural
process in which its neighbors start
nibbling away at its borders and start
grabbing its territories it is simply a
natural process in India when the Gupta
Empire started declining neighboring
kingdoms started nibbling away at his
territory when the cha Empire declined
in in the southern parts of India its
neighboring Kingdom started nibbling
away its territory and taking over
chunks of its territory and similarly
when the kusan Empire declined the
sasanians started taking its territory
that's just a natural process all right
that happens everywhere similarly during
the time of daros during the time of the
hakam Manish Empire there was a period
of time when India was politically
fragmented India was politically weak
and there was this absence this vacuum
of power which somebody had to fill so
the so the Ain the Hamish Dynasty they
did this firstly under cus and darus and
uh and later yeah Cyrus and daras did
that so it was a natural process that
there is an absence of power here so I
need to take over this territory and
stabilize it and obviously it expands my
territory I can get more resources and
wealth and revenue so why not so that
was a natural process but you will never
see any instance in history where the
Persians before the Arabic Conquest
launched an actual invasion of
India okay the way they launched
invasions of Greece and Anatolia a
proper well thought out well planned
well supplied and provisioned military
campaign that would last several years
and the objective was to take over all
of Greece all of Anatolia they never had
any campaign like that to take over
India or even a part of India what
happened like the the incidents you're
mentioning the Ain invasion of the
gandhar region and the Indus Valley
region and the sassanian invasion of
kushan Empire all of that was just
natural processes that the natural
processes that have throughout
history moved the boundaries between
Empires and kingdoms just a natural
process it was never a well thought out
invasion they just expanded as far as
the could because there was a decline of
power here but they never said that okay
let me go and Conquer matura let me go
and Conquer pbra never ever did they
even imagine doing that that's the
difference but yeah excellent question
excellent
question okay Sor borya says mvn Krishna
claims that an Indian king king of the
Indus site ruled Egypt and Babylon
according to his decipherment of a seal
from the Indus Valley where he read the
king's name is susak from ran of
Rajasthan and he related him to Egyptian
king shishak descendant of meses masaa
of IND the script he deciphered and
according to him the names of the C
cities he ruled in Egypt are also
mentioned what's your view on this so uh
mvn Krishna Ra was an Indian historian
and probably archaeologist from the 20th
century and he claimed to have
deciphered the sarasa Hindu script the
so-called Indus Valley script or harapan
script now I'm not sure I've not looked
into this personally as I'm not looked
into the the alleged disa forment myself
so I'm not sure how right or wrong it
is but clearly it is not recognized
right now as a valid disa forment so
maybe maybe it was not correct maybe I'm
just saying I've not seen it myself and
according to his uh research apparently
he uh correlated certain names that he
found like uh uh the king Egyptian king
shishak he correlated that with a
deciphered indust valley
seal in which there was an King's named
suaka well I don't know how true it is
we should not just dismiss such uh such
research out of hand maybe there could
be some some truth to it but it needs to
be investigated thoroughly properly
essentially if it was an Indian king who
ruled
Egypt then you would find some Indian
artifacts Indian origin artifact some
kind of clues in Egypt that would bring
bring forth a link with
India and as far as I know we haven't
found that it doesn't mean the absence
of evidence doesn't prove the evidence
of absence but well we do need evidence
to uh to legitimize a claim so as of now
I would say that this claim hasn't been
proven true it doesn't mean it is
incorrect but yeah that's the situation
right now but I we know for a fact that
there were connections and contacts
between between India and Egypt
uh Indian the Indian zebu cattle first
appear in Egypt around 2,000 BC 2000 BC
so that's during the Saras Hindu phase
of India's history obviously right so in
these cattle did not arrive them there
in Egypt by themselves okay let's go for
a walk and we'll go to Egypt let us go
for a walk and we will go to Egypt
that's not like what what cattle do
catle travel with human beings so
obviously Indians went all the way to
Egypt and introduced this catle there
and they were very popular and then you
have these indust these zebu cattle
appearing all over Africa and today you
have hybrid cattle all over Africa which
have zebu genes and so the first uh
evidence of zebu cattle in in Egypt goes
back at least 4 thou 4,000 years so
clearly there was significant uh
connectivity and connections and
relations of trade whatever between
India ancient India and ancient Egypt
but that doesn't
uh
corroborate this particular claim I'm
it's possible this claim is correct but
we don't have evidence thus far all
right that's what I would
say okay another question by s boria a
few people say that the harons were not
Vic as they speak a Proto dravidian
language and it confirm it is confirmed
from the Mesopotamian accounts that as
the trade with the Indians the harappans
and import sesame oil from haraa they
called it by by the name ilha and in
today in Tamil we call it IL so
apparently that proves that the harapan
spoke a Proto dravidan language and they
were not uh
vidc look I have always said this so
many times that India was not a
disconnected place okay look at
India if you see today's India you have
it's a gigantic subcontinent sized
nation state you have so many
languages spread
across uh the the subcontinent in
different parts of the sub subcontinent
east west north south right and yet it
is completely networked completely
interconnected in so many different
ways so everybody in every part of India
is aware of people from every other part
of India and it's completely
interconnected and I assure you that
4,000 5,000 years ago we had the same
thing it's not like we had different
civilizations one kiladi civilization
here and one Puri civilization there and
one Indus Valley Civilization here and
the Chandra gugar civilization there
every new archaeological site they
discover they call it they call it a new
civilization that is ridiculous that is
reible that is asinine that is laughable
India was a single civilization and it's
possible that you had people from
various parts of India who were trading
with Mesopotamia from the Saraswati
Hindu region because it is kind of
bordering Mesopotamia almost after you
cross Iran
Persia marashi ilam and so on right so
it's possible that the protot speaking
people were there and they were the ones
possibly who were bringing in sesame oil
and taking it all the way to the
Mesopotamian region and maybe their word
became became commonly used in
Mesopotamia right that's also a
plausible explanation to this the point
is this
look how will we
once and for
all determine what language was spoken
in the Saraswati synu region during that
period of our
history very simple when the script is
deciphered that's it that's all it will
take decipher the script and the answer
is right in front of you so the question
is every script in the world ancient
script has been deciphered but why not
the script what is preventing people
from deciphering the script is the
question I am I am patient I'm willing
to wait another 50 years the script will
be deciphered and when it's deciphered
well that will give us the answer if it
is protot I will accept it happily that
is prot Tamil or whatever a dravidian
language if it is sanskrit well you
better accept
it so that's it okay that's is that is
the only thing that's going to be the
clinching evidence of what language was
spoken in the Saras Hindu region during
that phase of our of our
history okay I've got so many other
questions I don't think I'll be able to
take all of them I've got
only 16 minutes
left
uh let's take some more questions of
course
uh okay s borya once again can Sanskrit
become an eii language artificial
intelligence language look AI is based
on mathematics and statistics Okay so
you can't use natural languages in
that what is what are these chat Bots
what what are these large language
models these are bun gigantic Bunches of
equations and algorithms algorithms are
are Bunches of statistical equations
okay mathematical equations uh about
statistics it's a lot of M Matrix
manipulation matrix multiplication
calculations of all kinds that happen
behind the scenes and there's
reinforcement training all kinds of
various kinds of training that is done
and then that's how these chat Bots be
become proficient and they seem to have
cracked the they seem to have passed the
touring test okay so uh and what are
these chat Bots fed they are they
fed tremendous amount of amounts of
text uh most of it in the English
language and obviously in other
languages as well I mean I'm sure that
if you go to chat GPT whichever version
we have today and you feed it a bunch of
Hindi text then it'll be able to
possibly give a reasonably good
translation into English and vice versa
I'm sure sure I would like to see a
large language model trained exclusively
on Sanskrit text we have a tremendous
amount of Sanskrit
text all the vas all the Opanas all the
puranas all the whatever else we have
tremendous amounts of srit texts why not
train a large language model on Sanskrit
texts
only and then you can give it other
abilities as well W that be great I
would like to see that happen but
somebody has to fund it right in in
India people want to fund all the wrong
kinds of things so anyway so I would
like that to happen and such Sanskrit is
the most precise algorithmically precise
language in human history thanks to the
the rules of of
Panini so you do that you do that with
classical Sanskrit and Vic Sanskrit then
it may actually even up even end up
deciphering the harapan
text that may happen uh yeah so right
okay this is a large question by Karthik
I really love the way you share your
knowledge and Science and geopolitics
thank you I'm sorry to ask a personal
question I would if you would like to
answer I live in a remote City in
Switzerland so far I'm doing well in my
life my first child was born in my early
40s I would like to ask you how to raise
my child with bhatha values and culture
as parents we are so busy in our busy
corporate work schedules it's very
challenging for me in the Western World
to teach the child about our culture and
values I'm also not thinking to go back
to India as of now because of our
education system and Liv standards
although the education system is very
good here in the academics but I feel
it's more materialistic I have the
greatest respect for our sanatan Dharma
which is the foundation of the core
values of my life despite my of my busy
schedules I'm trying to find a balance
to learn more and more about our history
and culture so that I can pass on this
knowledge to my child I heard opinions
from different Bara intellectuals and
your opinion is highly appreciated okay
uh yeah this is a dilemma that everybody
faces whether you're in the west or even
in India even even in Bat how do
I raise my
kid in such a way that my kid will have
an appreciation and respect and a solid
grounding in his or her own ancestral
culture and values that's a question
right now today if you look at even if
you look at bhat if you look at India
people are terribly deracinated why are
they deracinated
the question you to ask is why are
Indian kids today deracinated and not in
touch with their their
culture firstly because of the education
system which is in a foreign language it
is a foreign education system it's not
an Indian education system it doesn't
teach you anything about Indian history
or Indian culture or Indian philosophy
or Indian values in Indian morality
Indian ethics nothing there is nothing
Indian about the Indian education system
it's the only education system in the
world today that doesn't teach children
their own culture
and it the education is in a language
that's a foreign language I mean you can
have an education in your mother tongue
but then you won't get any jobs because
you won't be able to speak English
effciently so everybody wants their kids
to go in an English medium school and
it's typically going to be a so-called
conent school where they will fill these
kids heads with foreign values and
culture and you know whatever else right
so how do you ensure that kids in
India have a grounding in their culture
first of all make them and abroad as
well obviously it applies to all kids
firstly make them learn their own mother
tongue reading and writing spend half an
hour a day one hour a day and once they
have a solid grounding in that after a
couple of years make sure they learn the
basics of
Sanskrit and once they Sanskrit is the
easiest language to learn by the way you
know it's been made out artificially to
be a difficult language it's the easiest
language to world to to
learn okay so teach them their own
mother tongue reading and
writing and then teach them the basics
of Sanskrit if if possible proper
Sanskrit and then it's going to be
almost impossible for them and if you do
this at an early age from an early age
from the age of five or six by the time
they're 10 they'll be solid they'll have
a solid grounding in their culture and
that's going to be part of their life
forever as long as they as they they
live so that's what you do and then once
they have an understanding of the mother
tongue and the Sanskrit language then
you can expose them to various texts in
this language the ramayan the Mahabharat
Etc you do that then it's impossible for
the kid to not have an appreciation of
Bara values and culture and their
ancestral heritage that's what I would
say you need to do obviously it's easier
said than done okay today we have so
many distractions especially for kids
they're all scrolling up and down
screens you know iPad kids the the Gen Z
and whatnot it's really really difficult
gen Alpha all that but yeah I mean
that's a problem everybody faces and we
have to make it happen that's what I
would say all right all the best
sir
um Tas karney asks the age-old question
why is Alexander known as the great
while jingis Khan is called a barbarian
jingis Khan conquered more land than
Alexander why do historians call out
atrocities by Mongols in every article
about chingis Khan on the internet and
casually hug off what Alexander did in
persopolis to the people of Thieves in
the city of Ty and finally in India what
are your views on these kinds of biases
our history you know what Napoleon said
history is a set of Lies agreed upon
this was said by napoleo
bonapar okay Napoleon buap
if you were to okay I'll not go talk
about that so the point is
this the history we are taught is a
purely eurocentric version of History
whether it's India whether it's anywhere
in the world we are taught a eurocentric
version of history and the only thing
that matters in this eurocentric version
of history is the past 2,000 years
essentially there's nothing there was
nothing before the past 2,000 years it's
called prehistory according to them they
call it prehistory well according to
that even Alexander was a prehistoric
creature anyhow but but Alexander is the
great isn't he because he is one of the
great
conquerors of European
origin so I'll tell you what Alexander
did so his father dies okay his father
was Philip Philip of Macedon great guy
great conqueror Who had who had made
plans to conquer Persia so Philip of
Macedon before he can go on his uh
conquest of Persia is assassinated
during a military parade and before the
Assassin can be apprehended the Assassin
is also assass is also killed off so
then the question is has not been
answered till today who was behind the
murder of Philip of maedon was it was it
Alexander's mother was it Alexander
himself or somebody else blah blah blah
but then Alexander has to reconsolidate
his father's hold on Greece so he goes
to the city of Thieves which refuses to
submit to him so he besieges the city of
Thieves eventually after several months
I believe the city of thibes The Siege
finally ends with the breaking of the
walls Alexander goes and uh sells half
the population of Thieves into
slavery but he was merciful there
because he only sold them into slavery
then later on of in the Eastern
Mediterranean region the city of Ty in
present day Lebanon shall we go to the
map let's go to the
map the city of Ty which was an Island
City of the coast of
Lebanon where is Ty
today not here where is
it uh where is
tyer Ty here is Ty so it used to be an
Island City just off the coast so
Alexander besieges the city in The Siege
lasts several months it's a very
frustrating Siege because the Defenders
of tires are very Valiant in their
defense eventually finally when The
Siege succeeds and Alexander takes the
city of TI he crucifies tens of
thousands of people crucifies them to
death tens of thousands of innocent
people but I I can assure you that the
your textbooks will not talk about this
what Alexander did entire and then what
he did in in
Persia his horrific atrocities in Persia
and then when he tried to invade India I
mean when he was in the western borders
of India the kind of atrocities he
perpetrated on innocent people burning
entire Villages alive crucifying
crucifying people burning brah alive God
knows what kind of things he did
absolute barbaric brute of a person
Alexander Alexander the Greek but he's
considered to be he's called Alexander
the Great when it comes to Shir chingis
Khan he was the greatest conqueror of
all time and obviously when you conquer
you're going to fight people you're
going to destroy um armies you're going
to besiege cities things will happen but
these are the standard things that
happen in any
War but because chingis Khan was not
European because chingis Khan was not a
white man all kinds of stories are
spread about him he's alleged to be the
worst rapist in human history huh
because apparently lots of people in
Central Asia and various parts of the
world have a certain Mongol origin Hao
group okay and why is this so does it
mean that JIS Khan had violated so many
women it was his favorite pastime was it
so to prove that this is chingis Khan's
DNA you
need a sample of chingis Khan's physical
tissue bone hair or whatever do we have
it we don't have it so on what basis are
they making the claim just because there
is a mongolic origin Hao group that's
present far and wide the Mongolians were
a very small
nation the Mongolian Army was a 100,000
strong during the times of chingis KH a
100,000 strong you could fit the entire
Mongolian Army that conquered half the
world in the Eden Garden
stadium that was the number of men with
which he conquered the half the known
world and obviously they had wives and
whatever else in in these parts of the
world and it is such a small population
group that they will have very uniform
DNA so that explains why you have very
similar DNA all in such a vast region of
the world but they attributed to shis
Khan apparently raping women which is a
complete fabrication complete utter
fabrication and so on and Alexander
obviously what we need we know what he
did to persis he parur it's not persis
it's
parur the Greeks called it persopolis
because they have to mangle
everything right
araris he was the king's name was not
Aris it was arak shatra there's the king
zeris it was not zeris it
was Arya rames it was not Arya rames it
was Arya
ramna it was not nebu Kadar it was nabuk
kraar so they mangle all these words and
mangle everybody's name it was not
Sandra cotos it was Chandra
Gupta uh so yeah so whatever the Greeks
did is considered to be great whatever
Julius Cesar did in in his conquest of
gold in the Celtic regions is not called
genocide it's just called Conquest
reasonable Conquest but chingis Khan is
considered to be brute when Alexander in
a drunken night of drinking burned the
city of parur to to to Cinders it is
just not they blame it on a woman
apparently but not on on Alexander so
it's just double standards it's a purely
eurocentric view of the world it's a
very uh jealous view of the world
because there have been so many great
people who are not Europeans I mean look
at the way they talk about India as if
India has contributed nothing to the
world and so on but yeah we got to be
aware of this let them do let them
pursue their agenda but we should know
what they're up to and that's why I do
these things I I talk about this that's
why that's the reason why I do
it okay balam Putin
says what was the original culture of
Europe how did it get wiped out and by
whom okay let's go to map to understand
where Europe is okay we're talking about
Europe this region what was the original
culture of Europe before Christianity
before Christianity Europe had a single
overarching culture just like India has
a single overarching
culture which manifests itself locally
in a wide variety of different forms
look at
India India everywhere you go in India
the majority of of the population
worships the same gods and has the same
culture and civilizational values and
everything else but the manifestation of
this
civilizational uh of of this culture is
very different in very various different
parts of
India very diverse manifestations of the
same culture geographically the same
thing was there in Europe it was the
same culture with very different local
manifestations
okay and which culture which gods were
these these were nothing but the Old Vic
gods
which were woried across Europe
including in Anatolia including in
Greece including in Rome including in
the Germanic regions the Nordic regions
the Viking regions the Celtic regions
everywhere the Slavic regions it was the
same Gods as the old rvic gods who were
woried in a in a variety of different
forms in a variety of different names
and obviously some of these cultures
were more bloodthirsty than the others
and so on the the Christians called them
the pagans so that was the original
culture of of Europe you could call it
the old Indo European culture which
sprang out of India and lots of people
will not like what I say but deal with
it now what happened to this culture how
was it wiped out by whom was it wiped
out it was wiped out by the Christians
okay Christianity emerges out of
where um out of the Middle East out of
uh Bethlehem and Galilee and all this
region and eventually it becomes a a
movement kind of the local voke movement
in Rome and they alleged that the Romans
perpetrated all kinds of atrocities
against the Christians and there were
lots of Martyrs and all so they claimed
victimhood they claimed martyrdom and
eventually they took over the whole of
the Empire and eventually Christianity
became the dominant force in the Roman
Empire and the Roman Empire split into
two the Byzantine Empire which is the
eastern part of the Roman Empire which
was based in Constantinople present day
Turkey temporarily and there was the
Western Roman Empire which was based out
of Rome which became the Holy Catholic
Roman Empire so Rome never fell it
simply became the Vatican Empire and it
was this Vatican Empire in the all
powerful popes who conquered Europe
through Christianity and destroyed
smashed all of the old culture out of
Europe that is what happened so the
original culture of Europe was destroyed
smashed out of existence by the
Christians by the by the church
is what
happened okay let's take a one or two
more questions shall I take a few
questions from the from the live chat
I've taken already spent two hours
taking questions from the comments let's
take some questions from the live chat
so ladies and gentlemen's if you have
questions you want to ask me ask me now
in the live
chat D says how do you how to prevent
Hinduism from going extinct how to
prevent Hinduism from going going
extinct practice Hinduism practice and
promote Hinduism that's it and ensure
that your kids are exposed to
Hinduism and they actually
practice
it so you to teach them your mother
tongue you to teach them the basics of
Sanskrit and you to expose them to the
Mahabharat ramay and whatever your tra
family and local Traditions are and make
sure that they actually go to the temple
regularly and all that you have to
practice something to prevent it from
going extinct it's as simple as
that Kar nwat says your opinion on
homeschooling I think it's a very good
idea if you can pull it off it's very
hard to pull off homeschooling because
the parents need to either hire a
private tutor or to tutor the kids
themselves which is easier said than
done you need to spend a lot of time set
aside a significant amount of time for
doing that so if you can pull it off
it's a great option because the
schooling system in India is horrible it
will brainwash your children in in VY y
them and turn them into God knows what
Urban
knels um you know it will it will
completely alienate them from your own
culture your own roots from the from the
heritage of your own ancestors so
ideally if if possible you should do it
and you also need to ensure that your
kid is socialized well because
homeschooling is it kind of can isolate
your kids you know from other kids so
yeah that's that's a
thing okay
um Kiran bandagi Kiran bandagi says uh
in the past an asteroid hit and
destroyed most of nature maybe mother
earth created intelligent beings that is
humans to prevent to protect Earth
what's your take on this Theory I think
evolution is a natural process uh Mother
Earth doesn't need protection as such
and yeah so today we have let's let's
assume this theory is correct let's
assume that Mother Nature has created
humans to protect the Earth
because in the past asteroids destroyed
much of Nature and caused Extinction
events like the 66 million years ago
event the chalub impact event that
killed off the non avien
dinosaurs well if you look at that event
which happened 66 billion years ago it
killed off the non-avian dinosaurs but
the avien dinosaurs survived and they
are still
alive and that event did not kill off
the ancestors of the mammals which
includes our ancestors
so it did not kill everything off the
Aven dinosaurs are still out there
they're still out there I saw a few
today I saw a few avien dinosaurs today
and uh our our ancestors survived that
event
so that event happened 66 million years
ago now let's say in the future let's
say in three years time we are not aware
of it but an asteroid is going to come
and smash into our planet are we today
in a position to prevent that from
happening I tell you what we are not
so if Mother Earth created humans to
protect Earth why are we not in a
position to do
that we would need at least 5 to 10
years notice I would say ideally 10 20
years notice of an asteroid coming
towards Earth before before we can
actually take some proper action you
would either need to use a gravitational
tractor to displace to to to nudge the
asteroid in into a different trajectory
because nuclear weapons won't work this
simply won't work you can take the
biggest nuclear weapon you have the Char
bomba and detonate it on an asteroid it
will have no real effect the asterid
will still go and impact Earth but in a
million more pieces which may be even
more
harmful
so yeah
so it doesn't look like it's the case
right all right let's see some
other questions Anisha says the
Bangladeshi PM uh Mrs shikina spoke
about the CIA trying to make a Christian
State out of Bangladesh and Myanmar as
well as Northeast parts of India My
Views My Views are I wasn't aware of the
statement but if she has made the
statement she is 100%
right she is 100% right there's a whole
Civil War situation happening in Burma
right now bymar okay and US missionaries
are involved UK missionaries are
involved in this there is this entire
bunch of tribes in the northern part of
Myanmar let's go to the map who are
fighting the government of Myanmar
okay and this northern region is right
next to nagaland Manipur and India's Far
East and all these tribes are apparently
now Christian and there are these
evangelists at work over there who are
supporting these tribes these various
tribal and ethnic groups against the
government of Myanmar the military
government of Myanmar and we know that
the great Shri jawaharlal Neu spared no
effort into making into christianizing
large parts of our Far East mizoram is
completely Christian 99.8% or 99%
nagaland is almost entirely Christian
megala much of it is Christian uh
Manipur I would say the majority are
Christian
now and the those who are not Christian
in Manipur are under siege now and they
are under siege by foreigners who are
coming across the bo from across the
border in from Burma and these so-called
cookies are not even burmes because they
do not speak the burmes language they
don't not practice burmes culture they
don't even respect Burma
so uh there's a geopolitical game at
Play over here when it comes to the
Manipur issue it's not some
misgovernance or a Law and Order issue
you know in the 1980s and all when India
used to complain about Pakistani
terrorism to the Americans the Americans
used to say it's a Law and Order issue
you people are not able to take care of
the Law and Order in your state when it
was Pakistani terrorism that was being
funded by the Americans themselves so
similarly something else and something
similar is happening right now in this
region they want to destabilize and
Destroy Myanmar they want to destabilize
and and completely christianize the Far
East of India and the cookies are also
fighting the government of Bangladesh by
the
way so they want that in Bangladesh also
these cookies these ragtag tribals they
are fighting three countries they're
fighting Burma they're fighting India
and they're fighting Bangladesh if they
want to create an artificial fictitious
Nation called zaling gam which is cookie
land or whatever a nation in Christ okay
so what Bangladeshi PM is saying is 100%
factually
correct okay zavi quu says I am zavi
from kohima nagaland can you tell me
about how much gold can be found in
nagaland as per your Quick Knowledge I'm
not aware of the amount of gold that's
in nagaland uh this region this part of
of of India the Far East of India is
rich in natural resources there is oil
there is uh various kinds of metals
uh there could be gold I wasn't aware of
this there is definitely uranium and
whatnot so I think there could be a lot
and much of it has not even been
explored so you need to do some
prospecting Etc to find out how much of
what is available I don't think that's
been that's been done there and
obviously this is a very beautiful
region very pristine environments except
in Manipur where the poppy plantations
have destroyed the forest but in
nagaland I think it's still very very
clean and very safe and U so the nature
has been well preserved the ecology the
environment is reasonably well preserved
so if you discover big reserves of
whatever and you do mining it could kind
of affect the environment and that sort
of thing so that is one consideration
but at least we should be aware of
what's out there so I wasn't aware that
there could be gold in nagaland I will
look it up maybe I can take take this up
the next time but I wasn't aware of this
but I would not be surprised if you find
tremendous amounts of resources in this
region okay
uh
let's Noob Clash of Clan if Russia and
the US destroy each other what will
happen it'll destroy the world as simple
as that because if they destroy each
other it'll be nuclear war which will
destroy the whole world and we don't
want that to happen you know nuclear
weapons are not to be spoken of lightly
we never want the use of nuclear weapons
ever in the future because because you
don't know how dangerous they are they
will destroy the world
okay
um what else do we have what else what
else what
else radika says how do you think India
will take over Pakistan what are your
favorite geopolitics books I don't have
any geopolitics books favorite because
there are no books on geopolitics you
can read books by Kissinger you can read
books by uh
brazinski brzinsky you can read
books my favorite geopolitics books are
actually history books you study history
you will learn geopolitics uh how do you
think India will take over Pakistan
India doesn't want to take over Pakistan
in the near future okay Pakistan will
eventually collapse under its own weight
because it is an artificial Nation
there's too much Strife in Pakistan
there is too much oppression in Pakistan
and eventually it'll collapse on its own
and then you will have the emergence of
independent nations like balistan uh
pashtunistan which may reintegrate with
Afghanistan they will have independent
Sy and so on we don't want to
reintegrate these regions right now with
India because of the highly radicalized
population let them settle down for a
few decades and eventually the
subcontinent will reunite U through a
natural process right now we don't want
that we don't want to go to war with
Pakistan we don't want to trade with
Pakistan let Pakistan deal with its Fate
on its own it will collapse under its
own weight in due in due time through a
through a natural
process they just says you said that MI
was an atheist because of Chinese
sources but his coins show Trident on
them which Associates him with Shiva and
some inscriptions said that he bent head
only in front of Shiva opinions while
there are different interpretations of
history there is something called the
tamga in the honik culture t a m g h
let's let's take a look at that on the
screen shall we let's go to
Google okay and
let's one second not this Google let me
once again go back to screen
uh here we
are so what is a Tanga t a m g
ha Tanga honik Tanga right so it's an
abstract seal
honik so these are various symbols that
the Huns used these were like
uh these are like uh symbols that each
King every King had a symbol of his own
so many of these look like Trident and
this could perhaps be miira
coola and many of these guys had various
symbols that looked like Trident some of
them had the head of a elephant some of
them would have the head of a bull but
the Tanga is typically typically this
sort of symbol and some people would
interpret that as a trident but it may
not necessarily be a trident all
right but once again what we are told is
that m was a very cruel King he was an
atheist he it is said that the the
Buddhists despised Mula because of his
oppression and his heavy-handedness the
brahmins also despised Mula and it's
only after he died and his successors
came to power that things became good
and those successors were fully fully
Indian
so there are various different sources
and different interpretations that give
us different ideas of what actually was
there but I would say that
this trident like structure on his coins
could actually be his
TGA all right okay that brings us to the
end of today's session once again thank
you so much for all the questions as
always I cannot take everyone's
questions and I apologize to those of
you who have been asking I could not
take your questions but I will do more
of these live streams much more
frequently three more coming up next
week so keep attending hopefully
everybody gets to have their questions
answered by me so thank you so much and
I will see you the next live stream all
right right take care and I'll see you
soon and keep raising your standards